There are no clean getaways.
Drive is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Nicolas Winding Refn.
Driver is a skilled Hollywood stuntman who moonlights
as a getaway driver for criminals.
Though he projects an icy exterior, lately he's been warming up to a
pretty neighbor named Irene and her young son, Benicio.
When Irene's husband gets out of jail, he enlists
Driver's help in a million-dollar heist.
The job goes horribly wrong, and Driver must risk his life to protect Irene
and Benicio from the vengeful masterminds behind the robbery.
Driver, played by Ryan Gosling.
Irene, played by Carey Mulligan.
Shannon, played by Bryan Cranston.
Bernie Rose, played by Albert Brooks.
Standard, played by Oscar Isaac.
Blanche, played by Christina Hendricks.
Drive is a 2011 American action drama film directed by Nicolas Winding Refn.
The screenplay, written by Hossein Amini, is based on James Sallis's 2005 novel.
The film stars Ryan Gosling as an unnamed Hollywood stunt
driver who moonlights as a getaway driver.
He quickly grows fond of his neighbor, Irene (Carey
Mulligan) and her young son, Benicio.
When her debt-ridden husband, Standard (Oscar Isaac), is released from prison, the two men take part in what
turns out to be a failed million-dollar heist that endangers the lives of everyone involved.
The film co-stars Bryan Cranston, Albert Brooks,
Christina Hendricks, and Ron Perlman.
Producers Marc Platt and Adam Siegel optioned the source novel
after Siegel read a review from Publishers Weekly.
Adapting the book proved to be challenging for
Amini, as it had a nonlinear narrative.
Gosling, one of Platt's top casting choices, eventually signed on for the
lead, as he wanted to star in an action-oriented project.
Gosling played a pivotal role in the film's production, which included
hiring Refn as director and Beth Mickle as production designer.
Newton Thomas Sigel oversaw the principal photography, which started on September 25,
2010, was shot on location in Los Angeles, and ended on November 12.
Before its September 2011 release, Drive had been shown at the 64th
Cannes Film Festival, earning Refn the Best Director Award.
The film was praised for its direction, cinematography, performances (particularly Gosling and Brooks's), visuals, action sequences, and musical score;
however, some critics were appalled by its graphic violence and found it to be potentially detrimental to the film's box office success.
Nonetheless, the film was still a commercial success, grossing over
$81 million against a production budget of $15 million.
Several critics listed Drive as one of the best films of
2011, including the National Board of Review.
Its accolades include a nomination for Best Sound
Editing at the 84th Academy Awards.
The film has garnered a cult following since release.
The film explores themes of robbery, car mechanic,
stuntman, beaten to death, revenge.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.